A Guide to the Blue Ridge Sanatorium Collection 1920 - 1984
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
- STATE BOARD OF HEALTH COMMITTEE FOR BLUE RIDGE SANATORIUM MEETING MINUTES AND CONTRUCTION BIDS AND CORRESPONDENCE RE: RIGHT OF WAY WITH MONTICELLO 1924, 2 TLS, 2 TL, 1 AM 7 TMs (Box-folder 06-034)
  W. E. BROWN, WILLIAM F. SMITH,
- STATE BOARD OF HEALTH COMMITTEE FOR BLUE RIDGE SANATORIUM MEETING MINUTES AND CORRESPONDENCE 1923, 15 TMs, 29 TLS, 2 TL, 2 AM, etc. (Box-folder 06-035)
  W. E. BROWN, ENNION G. WILLIAMS
- STATE BOARD OF HEALTH COMMITTEE FOR BLUE RIDGE SANATORIUM MEETING MINUTES AND CONSTRUCTION BIDS 1922, 11 TMs, 21 TLS, 6 TL, 2 AM, etc. (Box-folder 06-036)
  W. E. BROWN; JOHN R. SAUNDERS; MONROE COUNTY TUBERCULOSIS SANATORIUM
- STATE BOARD OF HEALTH COMMITTEE FOR BLUE RIDGE SANATORIUM MEETING MINUTES AND CORRESPONDENCE AND BIDS 1921, 20 TM, 10 TLS, 2 Telegrams (Box-folder 06-037)
- LETTER FROM FRANCIS P. VENABLE TO H. T. MARSHALL 1920, 1 TL (Box-folder 06-038)
- ORGANIZATIONAL CHART 1979-80, 1 TM (EC) (Box-folder 07-001)
  VAMIK D. VOLCAN
- LEGISLATIVE PROPOSAL AND PROGRAMS PLANS FOR BLUE RIDGE SANATORIUM MARCH 1978, 187 TMs (EC), 1 TLS (EC), etc. (Box-folder 07-002)
  ROBERT HENDERSON, FORREST W. PITTS, THOMAS V. SELLARS
- LETTER FROM VAMIK D. VOLKAN TO MRS. NED F. BAUGHMAN, RE: PATIENT STORE 1979-1980, 1 TLS (EC) (Box-folder 07-003)
- INSTITUTE OF LAW, PSYCHIATRY AND PUBLIC POLICY 1981-82, 27 TMs (EC), 20 TLS (EC), etc. (Box-folder 07-004)
  RICHARD J. BONNIE, VAMIK D. VOLKAN, JOHN ASHLEY
- INSTITUTE OF LAW, PSYCHIATRY AND PUBLIC POLICY 1980, 61 TMs (EC), 3 TLS (EC), etc. (Box-folder 07-005)
  WALLER HUNT, MICHAEL K. MOORMAN, RICHARD MERRILL, NORMAN BURCH, J. I. LEVINE, NORMAN J. KNORR
- INSTITUTE OF LAW, PSYCHIATRY & PUBLIC POLICY 1979-80, 87 TMs (EC), 3 TLS, etc. (Box-folder 07-006)
  P. BROWNING HOFFMAN, VAMIK D. VOLKAN, STUART ALLEN, LISA MARZO, RICHARD J. BONNIE
- QUARTERLY MANAGEMENT REPORTS, BLUE RIDGE HOSPITAL 1978-79, 71 TMs (EC), 75 TMS, 2 TLS, etc (Box-folder 07-007)
  VAMIK D. VOLCAN, FRANK HEREFORD, MARY BROWN, CHARLES HAMNER, L. C. MANNING, J. HARRY MICHAEL
- LICENSED PRACTICAL NURSING PROGRAM 1978-79, 1 TLS (EC), 1 TmemoS (EC) (Box-folder 07-008)
  EDWARD SMITH, THOMAS V. SELLARS, J. I. LEVINE, ROBERT LAWHARNE
- DISASTER DRILL 1974, JUNE 7, 4 TMs (EC), 25 AMs (Box-folder 07-009)
  THOMAS V. SELLARS, K. M. HEATWOLE, H. YATES
- DISASTER DRILL 1974, NOVEMBER 29, 20 TMs (E), 3 TMS, 6 TMsS, etc. (Box-folder 08-001)
  THOMAS V. SELLARS, FORREST W. PITTS, JOHN CRISER
- DISASTER DRILL, PATIENT 'D1' FILE 1974, NOVEMBER 29, 3 Tags, 1 ID, 7 Amemos, etc. (Box-folder 08-002)
- DISASTER DRILL, PATIENT 'D2' FILE 1974, NOVEMBER 29, 1 Tag, 1 ID, 7 Ameno, etc. (Box-folder 08-003)
- DISASTER DRILL, PATIENT 'D3' FILE 1974, NOVEMBER 29, 2 Tag, 1 ID, 3 Amemo, etc (Box-folder 08-004)
- DISASTER DRILL, PATIENT 'D4' FILE 1974, NOVEMBER 29, 1 ID, 3 Amemo, etc. (Box-folder 08-005)
- DISASTER DRILL, PATIENT 'D5' FILE 1974, NOVEMBER 29, 3 Tags, 1 ID, 1 Amemo, etc. (Box-folder 08-006)
- DISASTER DRILL, PATIENT 'D7' FILE 1974, NOVEMBER 29, 1 Tag, 1 ID, 2 Amemos, etc (Box-folder 08-007)
- DISASTER DRILL, PATIENT 'D8' FILE 1974, NOVEMBER 29, 2 Tags, 1 ID, 3 Amemos, etc. (Box-folder 08-008)
- DISASTER DRILL, PATIENT 'D9' FILE 1974, NOVEMBER 29, 1 Tag, 1 ID, etc. (Box-folder 08-009)
- DISASTER DRILL 1973, DECEMBER 13, 32 TMs (EC), 9 TMS, 3 TM, etc. (Box-folder 08-010)
- DISASTER DRILL, PATIENT '1' FILE 1973, DECEMBER 13, 1 Tag, 2 Admissions forms, etc. (Box-folder 08-011)
- DISASTER DRILL, PATIENT '2' FILE 1973, DECEMBER 13, 1 Tag, 2 Admission Forms (Box-folder 08-012)
- DISASTER DRILL, PATIENT '3' FILE 1973, DECEMBER 13, 1 Tag, 4 Amemos, etc. (Box-folder 08-013)
- DISASTER DRILL, PATIENT '4' FILE 1973, DECEMBER 13, 1 Tag, 2 Admission Forms, etc (Box-folder 08-014)
- DISASTER DRILL, PATIENT '5' FILE 1973, DECEMBER 13, 1 Tag, 1 Admission Card, etc. (Box-folder 08-015)
- DISASTER DRILL 1973, DECEMBER 13, 1 Tag, 2 Printed Forms, etc. (Box-folder 08-016)
- LEGISLATIVE PROPOSAL - TRANSFER OF BLUE RIDGE SANATORIUM TO UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA 1978-79, 2 TMs (Box-folder 08-017)
- INSTITUTE OF LAW, PSYCHIATRY & PUBLIC POLICY 1978-79, 9 TMs, 4 TLS (EC), 5 TLS, etc. (Box-folder 08-018)
  P. BROWNING HOFFMAN; CURRICULUM VITAE OF LOREN ROTH; VAMIK D. VOLKAN, NORMAN J. KNORR, WILFORD W. SPRADLIN
- DISASTER DRILL 1976, SEPTEMBER 3, 8 TLS, 14 TMs (EC) 14 AMs, etc. (Box-folder 08-019)
  ROBERT LAWHORNE, JUDITH HOFFMAN, FORREST W. PITTS, THOMAS V. SELLARS
- DISASTER DRILL, PATIENT '1' FILE 1976, SEPTEMBER 3, 3 Tags, # Amemos, etc. (Box-folder 08-020)
- DISASTER DRILL, PATIENT '2' FILE 1976, SEPTEMBER 3, 3 Tags, 5 Amemo, etc. (Box-folder 08-021)
- DISASTER DRILL, PATIENT '3' FILE 1976, SEPTEMBER 3, 3 Tags, 1 Amemo, etc. (Box-folder 08-022)
- DISASTER DRILL 1975, NOVEMBER 2, 14 TMs, 78 TMs (EC), 6 TLS, etc (Box-folder 08-023)
  THOMAS V. SELLARS, GEORGE MOORE, DAVID MOORE, FORREST W. PITTS, GENE CARPENTER, WILLIAM SHEPPE, JOHN HARLAN
- DISASTER DRILL, PATIENT '1' FILE 1975, NOVEMBER 2, 2 Tags, 4 Printed Forms, etc. (Box-folder 09-001)
- DISASTER DRILL, PATIENT '2' FILE 1975, NOVEMBER 2, 3 Tags, 4 Printed Forms, etc. (Box-folder 09-002)
- DISASTER DRILL, PATIENT '3' FILE 1975, NOVEMBER 2, 3 Tags, 4 Amenos, etc. (Box-folder 09-003)
- DISASTER DRILL, PATIENT '4' FILE 1975, NOVEMBER 2, 2 Tags, 4 Amemos, etc. (Box-folder 09-004)
- DISASTER DRILL, PATIENT '5' FILE 1975, NOVEMBER 2, 2 Tags, 1 Admission Form (1CC) (Box-folder 09-005)
- DISASTER DRILL, PATIENT '6' FILE 1975, NOVEMBER 2, 2 Tags, 2 Admission Sheets, etc. (Box-folder 09-006)
- DISASTER DRILL, PATIENT '7' FILE 1975, NOVEMBER 2, 2 Tags, 1 Printed Form, etc. (Box-folder 09-007)
- DISASTER DRILL, PATIENT '8' FILE 1975, NOVEMBER 2, 1 Tag, 2 Admission Forms (1CC) (Box-folder 09-008)
- DISASTER DRILL, PATIENT '9' FILE 1975, NOVEMBER 2, 3 Tags, 6 Printed Forms, etc. (Box-folder 09-009)
- DISASTER DRILL, PATIENT '10' FILE 1975, NOVEMBER 2, 2 Tags, 2 Admission Forms, etc. (Box-folder 09-010)
- TUBERCULOSIS SERVICE, BLUE RIDGE HOSPITAL 1981-82, 102 TM(EC), 11Tmemo, 4 TLS, etc. (Box-folder 09-011)
  VAMIK D. VOLKAN, C. F. WINGO, EDWARD HOOK, MUNSEY WHEBY, CHARLES HESS
- TUBERCULOSIS UNIT - BLUE RIDGE HOSPITAL 1978-79, 57 TMs(EC), 3 TMs, 9 TLS, etc. (Box-folder 09-012)
  VANIK D. VOLKAN, THOMAS ALDRICH, ROBERT HENDERSON, DUDLEY ROCHESTER, W. APPERSON
- TUBERCULOSIS UNIT - BLUE RIDGE HOSPITAL 1979-80, 44 TMs(EC), 10 TMs, 8 TLS, etc. (Box-folder 09-013)
  ROBERT HENDERSON, VAMIK D. VOLKAN, EDWARD HOOK
- PROJECT STATUS REPORT, BLUE RIDGE HOSPITAL 1980, AUGUST 1, 1 Amemo, 1 Project Report (Box-folder 09-014)
- HOSPITAL INFECTIONS 1975, DECEMBER 9, 5 TMs(EC) (Box-folder 09-015)
- TUBERCULOSIS, THE GREAT WHITE PLAGUE no date, 253 TMs (Box-folder 10-001)
  HISTORY OF BLUE RIDGE SANATORIUM AND BLUE RIDGE HOSPITAL
- TUBERCULOSIS, THE GREAT WHITE PLAGUE no date, 253 TMs (Box-folder 10-001a)
- AGENDAS AND MINUTES, ADMINISTRATIVE COORDINATING COMMITTEE 7/3/1978-11/18/1981, 284 TMs(EC), 14 TMs, 1 Amemo (Box-folder 10-002)
  K. M. HEATWOLE, ALICE OWENS, JOHN GARVER
- BUDGET PLANNING, MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS 1955-84, 102 TMs, 22 AMs, 26 Tables, etc. (Box-folder 10-003)
  JAMES S. KENNAN, JOHN MCCUTCHEON, FORREST W. PITTS, DENNIS SCOTT, A. T. BRUNS; PHOTOGRAPH OF DABNEY MINOR TRICE, FOUNDER OF MOORE'S BROOK SANITARIUM, INC.; OPIUM ORDER FORMS
- SAMPLE MEDICAL EXAM, ARTICLE REFERENCE MATERIALS 1953-56, 1 TLS, 1 TL, 7 TMs (Box-folder 10-004)
  E. W. WHITNEY, WALTER KLINGMAN,
- MEDICAL NOTES AND LECTURES OF WALTER O. KLINGMAN ca. 1953-55, 41 TMs, 37 AMs, 1 TL (Box-folder 11-001)
  DONALD B. TOWER
- AN APPROACH TO A CONTINUING CHALLENGE TO NEUROLOGY BY WALTER O. KLINGMAN no date, 19 TM (Box-folder 11-002)
  WALTER O. KLINGMAN
- STATE HEALTH COMMISSIONER, L. J. ROPER, CORRESPONDENCE WITH FRANK B. STAFFORD AUGUST 1946 - DEC. 1948, 61 TLs, 48 TLS, 18 TM, 2 AM, etc. (Box-folder 11-003)
  HARRIS HART, CHARLES SCOTT
- NARCOTICS, PURCHASE OF, TAX EXEMPTIONS FOR, DEPARTMENT OF TREASURY, BUREAU OF NARCOTICS REGULATIONS 1942-49, 85 TLs, 25 TLS, 13 TM, 3 AM, etc. (Box-folder 11-004)
  FRANK B. STAFFORD, L. J. ROPER, STUART CRENSHAW, B. F. LOWRY
- STATE HEALTH COMMISSIONER, L. J. ROPER, CORRESPONDENCE WITH FRANK B. STAFFORD 1949, 24 TL, 18 TLS, 20 TM, 3 AM, etc. (Box-folder 11-005)
- STATE HEALTH COMMISSIONER, MACK I. SHANHOLTZ, CORRESPONDENCE WITH CHARLES G. PEARSON 1954-62, 133 TL, 83 TLS, 5 AM, 9 TM, etc. (Box-folder 11-006)
  JOSEPH BARRETT, MRS. W. B. SPONG
- STATE HEALTH COMMISSIONER, MACK I. SHANHOLTZ, CORRESPONDENCE WITH FRANK B. STAFFORD 1951-53, 51 TL, 37 TLS, 3 TM, 1 Tmemo, etc. (Box-folder 11-007)
- STATE HEALTH COMMISSIONER, L. J. ROPER, CORRESPONDENCE WITH FRANK B. STAFFORD 1950, 67 TL, 42 TLS, 15 TM, etc. (Box-folder 12-001)
- INTERNS 1934-41, 72 TL, 30 TLS, 27 ALS, 12 TMs, etc. (Box-folder 12-002)
  FRANK B. STAFFORD, JEROME GOODMAN, ALBERT STEINER, J. F. GRAFF, MACK I. SHANHOLTZ, CHARLES G. PEARSON
- INTERNS 1926-33, 17 TMs, 46 ALS, 31 TLS, etc. (Box-folder 12-003)
  CHARLES G. PEARSON, FRANK B. STAFFORD, ROBERT SMITH, W. L. DUNN, W. E. BROWN
- MASONIC RELIEF FOUNDATION 1926-27, 6 TMs, 1 TL (Box-folder 12-004)
  GEORGE W. WRIGHT MEMORIAL PAVILION; W. E. BROWN, J. E. W. TIMBERMAN, E. G. WILLIAMS
- NURSES TRAINING SCHOOL 1941-64, 85 TLs, 48 TLS, 15 ALS, 18 TMs, etc. (Box-folder 12-005)
  CHARLES G. PEARSON, LOUISE RAY, MABEL MONTGOMERY, MACK I. SHANHOLTZ
- INTERNS 1923-46, 21 ALS, 19TL, 14 TLS, 7 TM, etc. (Box-folder 12-006)
  FRANK B. STAFFORD, CHARLES CAKE, W. E. BROWN, E. C. HARPER
- INTERNS 1942, 15 TMs, 20 TL, 12 TLS 5 ALS, etc. (Box-folder 12-007)
  CHARLES G. PEARSON, CHESTER KEEFER, FRANK B. STAFFORD, GEORGE WHEELER, HUGH MORGAN
- MISCELLANEOUS PAMPHLETS, ARTICLES AND MATERIALS no date, 50 TMs, 1 TL etc. (Box-folder 12-008)
- GOVERNING BODY PLANNING COMMITTEE 1977, FEB.21-1978, FEB.28, 13TminutesS, 7 TLS(EC), etc. (Box-folder 13-001)
  THOMAS V. SELLARS, EDWARD HOOK, RAY HUNT, DUDLEY ROCHESTER, WILLIAM HARTON, JAMES KENLEY
- X-RAY SERVICE ORGANIZATION POLICY PROCEDURE 1970, JULY 2-1978,FEB.24, 98 TMs(EC), 8 TMs 3 TLS(EC),etc. (Box-folder 13-002)
  FORREST W. PITTS, T. C. KIM, KENNETH HEATWOLE, THOMAS V. SELLARS, HAROLD BERK, JOHN CRISER
- ANNUAL REPORT BLUE RIDGE SANATORIUM 1978, JUNE 30, 11 TMs (Box-folder 13-003)
  FORREST W. PITTS, THOMAS V. SELLARS, JAMES KENLEY
- ANNUAL REPORT BLUE RIDGE SANATORIUM 1977, JUNE 30, 16 TMs (2 copies), 13 TMs (Box-folder 13-004)
- ANNUAL REPORT BLUE RIDGE SANATORIUM 1976, JUNE 30, 13 TMs (2 copies) (Box-folder 13-005)
- ANNUAL REPORT BLUE RIDGE SANATORIUM 1975, JUNE 30, 17 TMs (2 copies) (Box-folder 13-006)
  FORREST W. PITTS, THOMAS V. SELLARS, MACK I. SHANHOLTZ
- ANNUAL REPORT BLUE RIDGE SANATORIUM 1974, JUNE 30, 17 TMs (2 copies) (Box-folder 13-007)
- ANNUAL REPORT BLUE RIDGE SANATORIUM 1973, JUNE 30, 18 TMs (2 copies) (Box-folder 13-008)
  FORREST W. PITTS, MACK I. SHANHOLTZ
- ANNUAL REPORT BLUE RIDGE SANATORIUM 1972, JUNE 30, 15 TMs, 2 TM, 2 TLS(EC), etc. (Box-folder 13-009)
- ANNUAL REPORT BLUE RIDGE SANATORIUM 1971, JUNE 30, 19 TMs (3 copies) (Box-folder 13-010)
- ANNUAL REPORT BLUE RIDGE SANATORIUM 1970, JUNE 30, 35 TMs (2 copies) (Box-folder 13-011)
- ANNUAL REPORT BLUE RIDGE SANATORIUM 1969, JUNE 30, 15 TMs (Box-folder 13-012)
  RAYMOND S. BLACKMAN, MACK I. SHANHOLTZ
- ANNUAL REPORT BLUE RIDGE SANATORIUM 1968, JUNE 30, 16 TMs (Box-folder 13-013)
- ANNUAL REPORT BLUE RIDGE SANATORIUM 1960, JUNE 30, 24 TMs (Box-folder 13-014)
- ANNUAL REPORT BLUE RIDGE SANATORIUM 1950, JUNE 30, 18 TMs (Box-folder 13-015)
- ANNUAL REPORT BLUE RIDGE SANATORIUM 1940, JUNE 30, 10 TMs (Box-folder 13-016)
- ANNUAL REPORT BLUE RIDGE SANATORIUM 1930, JUNE 30, 14 TMs (Box-folder 13-017)
- ANNUAL REPORT BLUE RIDGE SANATORIUM 1921, SEPTEMBER, 13 TMs (Box-folder 13-018)
- CORRESPONDENCE OF THOMAS V. SELLARS 1972, APRIL 17-21, 3 TLS, 1 TLS(EC), ! Amemo, etc. (Box-folder 13-019)
  BENJAMIN CULLEN, FORREST W. PITTS, MACK I. SHANHOLTZ, THOMAS V. SELLARS
- CONTINUING EDUCATION 1975-76, 69 TMs(EC), 15 TLS, etc. (Box-folder 14-001)
  FORREST W. PITTS, KENNETH M. HEATWOLE, LOIS MEUSCHKE, SALLY PERKINS, MYRA CLARK
- CONTINUING EDUCATION 1978, 1 TL, 1 Tmemo, etc. (Box-folder 14-002)
  FORREST W. PITTS, BRIDGET FLOOD
- CONTINUING EDUCATION 1977, 21 TMs(EC), 8 TLS, 4 TLS(EC),etc. (Box-folder 14-003)
  RAYMOND S. BLACKMAN, KENNETH M. HEATWOLE, FORREST W. PITTS
- BLUE RIDGE SANATORIUM MEDICAL DENTAL STAFF, CONTINUING EDUCATION 1971-74, 86 TMs(EC), 36 TLS, 2AMs, etc. (Box-folder 14-004)
  FORREST W. PITTS, WILLIAM APPERSON, KARL MENK, MYRA CLARK, MARY TUCKER
- MEDICAL STAFF CREDENTIALS 1975, DEC.-1977 DEC., 144 TMs, 1 Tmemo, 9 TLS, etc. (Box-folder 14-005)
  FORREST W. PITTS, KENNETH M. HEATWOLE, JAMES RITZ, JAMES KENLEY, RAYMOND S. BLACKMAN
- CLINICAL STAFF BYLAWS, RULES, REGULATIONS 1977, 144 TMs, 1 Tmemo, 9 TLS, etc. (Box-folder 14-006)
  FORREST W. PITTS, JAMES KENLEY, EDWARD SMITH
- BLUE RIDGE SANATORIUM LABORATORY PROCEDURE, MR. SELLARS 1978, 82 TMs(EC), 1 AM, etc. (Box-folder 15-001)
  FORREST W. PITTS, JUDITH HOFFMAN
- VIRGINIA GOVERNING BOARD, POLICY AND PROCEDURES MANUAL, BLUE RIDGE SANATORIUM 1971-74, 80 TMs, 4 TLS, 1 Brochure, etc. (Box-folder 15-002)
  MACK I. SHANHOLTZ, LILLIAN PEYTON, FORREST W. PITTS
- BLUE RIDGE SANATORIUM BUDGET EXHIBITS 1976-78, 66 TMs (Box-folder 15-003)
  JOHN MCCUTCHEON, THOMAS V. SELLARS, WILLIAM HARTON, J. STUART BARRET, THOMAS V. SELLARS
- BLUE RIDGE SANATORIUM BUDGET EXHIBITS 1974-76, 39 TMs (Box-folder 15-004)
- BLUE RIDGE SANATORIUM BUDGET EXHIBITS 1974-76, 40 TMs (Box-folder 15-005)
  JOHN RORER, JOHN MCCUTCHEON, THOMAS V. SELLARS
- BLUE RIDGE SANATORIUM BUDGET EXHIBITS 1972-74, 23 TMs (Box-folder 15-006)
- COMPREHENSIVE EPILEPSY PROGRAM, REP-NIH-NINDS-75-07, PROPOSED BY UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA MEDICAL CENTER 1975, APRIL 14, 323 TMs (Box-folder 15-007)
  FRITZ E. DREIFUSS